<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Verónica Lloréns Rico</title>
    <link>https://vllorens.github.io/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Verónica Lloréns Rico</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vllorens.github.io/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vllorens.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vllorens.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description>About me: I am a postdoctoral researcher at the VIB-KU Leuven Center for Microbiology, currently studying the functionality of the gut microbiota.
During my PhD studies I focused my research on a single bacterium, Mycoplasma pneumoniae. I studied the different mechanisms that this bacterium uses to regulate transcription, from canonical transcription factors to alternative mechanisms such as small RNAs or riboswitches. I analyzed hundreds of datasets from different omics, mostly RNA-seq and ChIP-seq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Publications</title>
      <link>https://vllorens.github.io/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vllorens.github.io/home/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awards</title>
      <link>https://vllorens.github.io/home/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vllorens.github.io/home/awards/</guid>
      <description>2018: Best Poster Award at the EMBO | EMBL Human Microbiome Conference. Poster title: A Mapping-based Human Metatranscriptomics Analysis Pipeline. Prize awarded by Molecular Systems Biology
 2018: Young Investigator Award from the Catalan Society of Biology (Premi al jove Investigador de la Societat Catalana de Biologia). Link to the press release.
 2017: PhD extraordinary Award, Universitat Pompeu Fabra. Thesis title: &amp;ldquo;Integrative understanding of transcription in a minimal cell model&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funding</title>
      <link>https://vllorens.github.io/home/funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vllorens.github.io/home/funding/</guid>
      <description>2023-2027: Ramón y Cajal fellowship (5 years), Ministerio de Ciencia e Innovación. Involvement: Fellowship awardee.
 2020-2023: FWO Senior Research Project (4 years). Promoter: Sabine Tejpar. Co-promoters: Verónica Lloréns-Rico and Sara Verbandt. Amount: 517.000€. Grant number: G0C9620N. Involvement: Co-promoter.
 2020-2023: FWO Senior postdoctoral Fellowship. 3 years postdoctoral fellowship that includes a 29.800€ bench fee for research project expenses. Grant number: 12V9421N. Involvement: Fellowship awardee.
 2020-2022: VIB Tech Watch Internal funding for Technology Development: 25.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outreach</title>
      <link>https://vllorens.github.io/home/outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vllorens.github.io/home/outreach/</guid>
      <description>2021: Outreach article: &amp;ldquo;Mycoplasma pneumoniae: quan menut no implica simple&amp;rdquo; in the magazine &amp;ldquo;Treballs&amp;rdquo; from the Catalan Society of Biology. This piece summarizes the major findings of my thesis (which granted me the Young Investigator Award of the Society in 2018) in layman&amp;rsquo;s terms. Link (in catalan) here
 2021: International Women&amp;rsquo;s day (8th of March). Virtual meetings with primary school students (10-11 years old) about my career as a woman doing research in biomedicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://vllorens.github.io/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vllorens.github.io/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>2021 (Scheduled): Microbiome Data Analysis Workshop. Location: UHasselt, Hasselt, Belgium. I will participate with tutorials and hands-on courses on data preprocessing and normalization.
 2019: Whole Cell Modeling Summer School. Location: CRG, Barcelona, Spain. I gave a hands-on workshop on ODE modeling of metabolic pathways.
 2017: Whole Cell Modeling Course. Location: CRG, Barcelona, Spain. I gave a hands-on workshop on ODE modeling of metabolic pathways.
 2016: Whole Cell Modeling Course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conferences and courses attended</title>
      <link>https://vllorens.github.io/home/conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vllorens.github.io/home/conferences/</guid>
      <description>2021: Microbiome Data Analysis Workshop - Online course https://mdawo.meetinghand.com/. Hands-on tutorials presented: &amp;ldquo;Frow raw data to OTU table&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Microbiome data visualisation, diversity, differential abundance and normalizations&amp;rdquo;. Seminar presented: &amp;ldquo;The issue of data normalizations&amp;rdquo;.
 2019: Exploring Human Host-Microbiome Interactions in Health and Disease. Cambridge, UK. Oral presentation: Quantitative microbiome profiling links gut microbial load to host inflammatory conditions.
 2018: EMBO|EMBL Symposium: The Human Microbiome. Heidelberg, Germany. Poster presentation: A Mapping-based Human Metatranscriptomics Analysis Pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://vllorens.github.io/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vllorens.github.io/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>